<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JAlgoArena on JAlgoArena Home</title>
    <link>https://jalgoarena.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JAlgoArena on JAlgoArena Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 19:22:55 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jalgoarena.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://jalgoarena.github.io/docs/quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalgoarena.github.io/docs/quick-start/</guid>
      <description>Deploy with Docker &amp; Nomad To deploy JAlgoArena - you will need to spin up Nomad and Consul clusters plus install Docker Engine.
 Make sure Docker is available on your machines Install Consul and Nomad clusters  use step0.sh to run locally on your laptop - it&amp;rsquo;s not recommended for production use case Install Consul Cluster Install Nomad Cluster  Once you have Nomad and Consul up and running, you may start running JAlgoArena external services:  Clone JAlgoArena-Nomad locally git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating Points</title>
      <link>https://jalgoarena.github.io/docs/calculating-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 19:22:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalgoarena.github.io/docs/calculating-points/</guid>
      <description>Problem Difficulty Firstly, base amount of points depends on problem difficulty:
 Difficulty Base Points   Easy 10 points   Medium 30 points   Hard 50 points   Time Penalty Secondly, amount of points which depends on time penalty:
 Elapsed Time / Time Limit Points Factor   &amp;gt;= 500 1.0   &amp;gt;= 100 3.0   &amp;gt;= 10 5.0   &amp;gt;= 1 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to JAlgoArena</title>
      <link>https://jalgoarena.github.io/blog/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 21:27:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalgoarena.github.io/blog/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to JAlgoArena – an open source algorithmic contest platform Hi there and welcome to JAlgoArena - this is first post just to mark the start point! There is lots of interesting technical considerations which are part of building such platform - especially if you have cloud native, high availability topics as the priorities for developing such platform!
So far it was used successfully in few companies to run globally spread on-premises hosted company wide algorithmic contest - and you know what?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacek Spólnik</title>
      <link>https://jalgoarena.github.io/company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalgoarena.github.io/company/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>